This is ErgoSNM
a split mechanical keyboard with an integrated trackball
This video will introduce the basic functions of the ErgoSNM
By pressing the left or right Fn key
you can switch to layer 2
which provides additional key functions
In layer 2
you can enter numbers using only your left hand
allowing your right hand to control the cursor
You can also adjust the volume
I placed the arrow keys on H J K L
just like in Vim
If you don't use Vim
this layout might feel unintuitive
But that's okay. You can customize any key using Vial to match your preference
Next are the mouse functions
press J & K to perform a left-click
K & L for a right-click
and J & L for a middle-click
The trackball is controlled with your thumb
allowing you to move the cursor while keeping your right hand on the home row
when you hold the Fn key
the trackball switches to scroll mode
enabling vertical scrolling
Alternatively, holding J & L also activates scroll mode
This means you can perform most mouse operations using only your right hand